Finding Aid for the Bound Manuscripts Collection LSC.0170
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Bowring, Sir John (1792-1872). Letters, signed, to various persons. **Letters to Charles Fauriel (London, 1824); C.B. Sheridan to Fauriel (); Charles Martin (). Accompanied by two portraits of Bowring., 1821-1845 December 30, 1824 May 20 ca. 1845; 170/225; Manuscript, 3 items.
  - Halliwell-Phillipps, James Orchard (1820-1889). Letters, signed, to various persons. **Letters to John Matthew Gutch; Henry Hunter; Holman; Panizzi and others, concerning manuscripts and prints., 1845-1881; 170/226; Manuscript, 6 items.
  - Holland, Sir Henry, bart. (1788-1873). Letters, signed to unknown gentleman (London, and s.a.)., November 29, 1870; 170/227; **Manuscript, 2 items.
  - Ellis, Sir Henry (1777/1869). Letters, signed, to Octavian Blewitt. **Concerning business, family and social engagements. Accompanied by letter to Mr. Routledge (London)., 1840-1867 April 6, 1864; 170/228; Manuscript, 10 items.
  - Roget, Peter Mark (1779-1869). Letter to unknown gentleman (University of London, ). **Accompanied by two portraits of Roget., November 15, 1837; 170/229; Manuscript, 1p.
  - Pembroke, Anne (Clifford) Herbert, Countess of (1590-1676). Notes written on the margins of a leaf from a 17th century travel book (pages 337-338 of volume 6, "Muscovy, Tartary, and Persia," of Adam Olearius. The voyages & travels of the ambassadors sent by Frederick Duke of Holstein, to the Great Duke of Muscovy, and the King of Persia… London: Printed for Thomas Dring, and John Starkey….., 1662). **Accompanied by three portraits of Anne Clifford., 170/230; Manuscript, 2pp.
  - Glaisher, James (1809-1903). Letters, signed, to Jabez Hogg. **Accompanied by portrait of Glaisher (astronomer, aeronaut, and meterologist)., 1865-1867; 170/231; Manuscript, 5 items.
  - Ballantyne, Robert Michael (1825-1894). Letters, signed, to various persons. **Letters to Richard Lees (Edinburgh ); Herbert Pentin (Harrow )., 1870-1892 December 1, 1870 October 12, 1892; 170/232; Manuscript, 3 items.
  - Wrangham, Francis (1769-1842). Letter, signed, to Messrs Baldwin & Company., August 21, 1821; 170/233; Manuscript, 1p.
  - Bantock, Sir Granville (1868-1946). Letters, signed, to Fred Kenyon and Gerald Cumberland. **Kenyon was the pseudonym of Charles Frederick Kenyon., 1908-1914; 170/234; Manuscript, 7 items.
  - Smith, Southwood (1788-1861). Letters, signed, to various persons (London, ). Accompanied by a holograph note listing speeches and tracts by Smith., 1845/1856; 170/235; Manuscript, 2 items.
  - Walter, John (1818-1894). Letters, signed, to various persons (Workingham )., 1872-1874; 170/236; Manuscript, 5 items.
  - Brydges, Sir Samuel Egerton, bart. (1762-1837). Letters, to Baron Turner & W.B. Cooke (London, ). With portraits of B. and Lady Isabella Anne Brydges., March 23, 1814; March 13, 1818; 170/237; Manuscript, 2 items.
  - Roebuck, John Arthur (1801-79). Letter, signed, to W.C. Leng (last page only) (s.l. s.a.). **With 3 portraits of Roebuck., 170/238; Manuscript, 1p.
  - Birrell, Augustine (1850-1933). Letters to Grant and Clement King Shorter (London s.a. and ). Accompanied by ephemera., November 13, 1924; 170/239; Manuscript. 2 items.
  - Birrell, Augustine (1850-1933). An Image of Shakespeare {review of book by Frank Mathews (London s.a.). **Accompanied by manuscript review of J.M. Dent's editions of W.H. Hudson's Far Away and Long Ago and Idle Days in Patagonia., 170/240; Manuscript, 10 leaves and Manuscript, 8 leaves.
  - Wyon, Benjamin (1802-58). Letters to J. Mayer & Mr. Vaughan. (3 letters to Mayer, )., April 12; December 6, 1839; 170/241; Manuscript, 4 items.
  - Portland, William Henry Cavendish-Bentick, 3rd Duke of (1738/1809). Letter, signed, to T. Townshend (London, ). **With letter to P. from T. Townshend (Whitehall September 22, 1782); Manuscript, Most Private; 2 portraits, genealogy of Portland., September 4, 1782; 170/242; Manuscript, 2pp. and Manuscript, 6pp.
  - Tupper, Martin Farquhar (1810-1889). Letters, signed, to various persons. **Twelve letters to the Chevalier de Chatelain (Guilford ); one to Colnaghi; one to Miss Goldhawk., 1852-1870 November 27,1852-October 19, 1870; 170/243; Manuscript, 14 items.
  - Young, Thomas, physicist and physician (1773-1829). Letter, signed, to S.P. Rigaud (London, )., April 25, 1829; 170/244; Manuscript, 1p.
  - Noble, Mark (1754-1827). A Dissertation upon the Church of Ireland as now united to that Of England (Barming, Kent, ). **Phillipps Manuscript no.9503., April 5, 1817; 170/245; Manuscript, 100pp.
  - Waldemar, Adolphus F. Survey Notes (San Gabriel, California, ). **Survey notes for Tract no.2 in the Township of San Gabriel., August-September 1861; 170/246; Manuscript.
  - Pantoja House, San Diego, California. Day Book (San Diego, ). **Daily accounts for the Pantoja House, a billiard parlor and saloon in New San Diego, owned by Charles J. Laning. There are numerous entries for purchases by William Heath Davis and Santiago E. Arguello., December 28, 1850-July 6, 1851; 170/247; Manuscript, 147pp.
  - Berchem, Marguerite van/Clouzot, Etienne. Mosiques chrétiennes du IVme au Xme siècle (Geneva )., 1924; *170/248; **Bound by Madeleine Kohn in full brown levant morocco, with inlays.
  - Jewellery. Various designs for Jewellery., ca. 1850; 170/249; Manuscript, 2 vol. **199 drawings, mounted.
  - Pailthorpe, Frederic W. (1837-1914). Drawings for Oliver Twist by Charles Dickens. **Original Watercolour drawings, mounted. 21 of these drawings were published separately from Dickens's work in London, 1886., ca. 1885; *170/250; 22 items.
  - Pailthorpe, Frederic W. (1837-1914). Collection of original drawings, sketches, tracings, water-colour paintings, and proofs, done to illustrate The Pickwick Papers, Great Expectations, Oliver Twist and other works of Charles Dickens (ca. 1880-1885). Accompanied by letter from Pailthorpe to Kitton (February 2, 1905)., *170/251; 178 items.
  - Alphabet Book (ca. 1850). Original pencil drawings. **Artist unknown. These drawings are of rural scenes, woods and ruins, each in the shape of the letters of the alphabet., 170/252; 26 leaves.
  - [Clarke, Joseph Clayton.] Original character illustrations to various works by Charles Dickens]. Drawn in colour by Kyd., *170/253-260; 276 drawings.
  - Templeman, Thomas (d. 1729). Templeman's Survey of the Globe: being an Accurate Mensuration of all the Empires, Kingdoms, Countries, States, Principal Provinces, Countries, and Islands in the World (Anthony Blinkhorn scripsit, ). Manuscript. **Apparently a copy of the printed edition, London 1729., 1735; 170/261
  - Patrick, General Marsena Rudolph (1811-1888). Diary. **The writer was a participant in the defence of Washington (1862), the second Manassas, and the Antietam campaign, etc., January 1, 1862-June 17, 1865; 170/262; Typescript carbon. 3 vol.
    The original Manuscript is in the Library of Congress.
    Restricted use.
  - Fowler, Joseph/Kimball, Charles D., General Merchandise. Ledger (Duarte, California 1894-1895). Ledger of accounts., *170/263; Manuscript.
  - Dryden, William S. Diary. **Diary as a farmer in Maine Prairie Township, Solano Company, California, including information on farming operations near San Diego, Lower California and in Alameda County near Oakland, California. Steamer trip to San Francisco. pp.1-59 include records of civil and criminal cases (March 1866/June 6, 1867) tried before Dryden as Justice of the Peace for Maine Prairie Township., January 1, 1870-April 14, 1872; *170/264; Manuscript, 179pp.
  - Riverside House, Riverside, California. Register. Printed form, filled in. **Names and addresses of hotel guests; interleaved with advertisements for various businesses, chiefly in San Bernardino and Riverside, California., March 4, 1882-September 23, 1882; *170/265
  - Zola, Emile (1840-1902). La censure., 170/266; Manuscript, 19 leaves.
  - Leech, John (1817-1864). Sketches by John Leech. **20 original pencil drawings with seven printed reproductions from Punch., ca. 1855-1860; *170/267; 14 leaves.
  - Eldon, John Scott, 1st Earl of (1751-1838). Legal and Political Commonplace Diaries., ca. 1785-1799; *170/268; Manuscript, 3 vol.
  - Issler, Anne (Roller) (b. 1892). Index to the Scrapbooks [2 through 6] of Margaret Isabella Balfour Stevenson, mother of R.L.S(tevenson)., *170/269; Photocopy of Typescript, 54 leaves.
  - Moore, George (1852-1933). Daphnis and Chloe. Perronik the Fool. (New York: Boni and Liveright, ). Accompanied by letter from Moore to Rex Whistler about the latter's proposed illustrations for the Perronik. The original illustrations belong to the UCLA Library., 1924; 170/270; Holograph corrections in ink on pp.132 sq., 138 sq., 143, 145 and 178.
  - Hogg, T. A Journal of a Voyage to the Nore with the East India Company's damag'd Tea in April 1828 (London ). Watercolour painting of two ships, the Coromandel and the Smith. An account in verse of the dumping of damaged tea., ca. 1828; 170/271; Manuscript, 36pp.
  - Heron-Allen, Edward (1861-1943). Original manuscripts of Verses (New York )., 1886/1889; *170/272; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912). Letters to Dead Authors: I. To Nathaniel Hawthorne. (St Andrews, Scotland, s.a.). **Not in Lang's book Letters to dead Authors. Unpublished?, 1893; 170/273; Manuscript, 17 leaves.
  - Swinburne, Algernon Charles (1837-1909). Lucifer. **A sonnet honouring Voltaire, first published in, 1904.; 170/274; Manuscript, 1 leaf.
  - West, Henry Hebard (1872-1958), comp. Handling President McKinley's Special on Los Angeles Division, Southern Pacific Railroad (Los Angeles, ). **A scrapbook compiled by West concerning the McKinley Special of, ca. 1888-1946 1901.; *170/275; Manuscript, etc. 229 leaves.
  - [Animated Book (?Paris ).] **By flipping the pages one sees a woman preparing for and entering her bath., ca. 1897; 170/276
  - Grahame, Kenneth (1859-1932). The Secret Drawer (London? ). **Published in an unknown periodical and then in the author's Golden Days., ca. 1893 1895; 170/277; Manuscript, 11 leaves.
  - Huxley, Aldous Leonard (1894-1963). Texts & Pretexts: an Anthology with Commentaries (London, ). **Mounted on front endleaf is a sheet of stationery with the last stanza of The Cicadas in Huxley's hand; signed., 1932; 170/278
  - Hamnett, Nina (1890-1956). Is She a Lady? (London ). **Autobiography, first published, London 1955., ca. 1955; *170/279; Manuscript/Typescript. 387 leaves.
  - Schindler, Andrew D. Report on Basin of Tulare Lake, California, with Analysis of its Potentialities for Reclamation and Irrigation (San Francisco )., January 1, 1917; *170/280; Typescript, etc. 133 leaves.
  - [Guidi, Jacopo di Giovanni de'?] Vita di Cosimo de' Medici primo Granduca dedicata a Francesco I suo figlio (Tuscany ). Cf. Ferrari, pp.126-127., ca. 1574/1587; *170/281; Manuscript, 193 leaves.
  - Medici, Carolo de. Account Book (Italy ). **Bank business. Cf. Ferrari, p.59., 1535-1536; *170/282; Manuscript, 109 leaves.
  - F., M.L. Pruebas de la religion de Jesuchristo contra los Espinosistas, y los Deistas. ... Tomo I: de la revelacion natual. Plan de est a obra (Spanish ). **Against Spinoza., ca. 1755-1800; *170/283; Manuscript, 103pp.
  - Ethiopic Church. Liturgy and Ritual. [Early Ethiopic liturgical manuscript]., 170/284; Manuscript, 165 leaves.
  - Bravo, Pedro/Bravo, Juan. Transcript of a Lawsuit in which it is proved that the Bravos are hidalgos and thus exempt from paying taxes to the town of Campanario (Granada )., 1608; *170/285; **Illuminated frontispiece.
  - Voltaire, François Marie Arouet de (1694-1778). La Pucelle d'Orleans: Poeme en vingt-un chants (Paris, ). **The poem was first published in 1762; the notes, by François Annibal Destouches, are apparently unpublished., 1832; 170/286; Manuscript, 119pp.
  - Thomson, James (1700/1748). The Seasons (London, ). **Double fore-edge painting: view of a lake with men fishing; fox-hunting scene., 1802; 170/287
  - Grenier, R. Grammaire Bambara (French Sudan 1896). **Apparently unpublished., 170/288; Manuscript, 106 leaves.
  - Sermons (London? ). **8 sermons by Dr. King, Mr. Day, Dr. Whyte, Mr. Osberstone, Dr. Willard, Mr. Wyall, John Burgess, and John Goodwin, copied by J.W., ca. 1615-1643; *170/289; Manuscript, 268 leaves.
  - Recueil de diverses lettres et autres pieces touchant histoire, anecdote du regne de Louis XIIII (France ). **Copied by M. Monteil., ca. 1720; *170/290; Manuscript, 317 leaves.
  - Collection of six pieces on historical subjects (French )., ca. 1600-1670; 170/291; Manuscript, 146 leaves.
  - Caraccioli, Tristano (ca. 1436-ca1517). Opera omnia (Italy s. XVII). **On historical subjects mostly relating to the nobility of Naples. Cf. Ferrari, pp.59-61., *170/292; Manuscript, 204 leaves.
  - Bickerstaff, Roger. A Tour thorugh North Wales during the Summer of 1801. Vol. 2., 170/293; Manuscript, 75 leaves.
    **vol.1 is missing.
  - Dejean, Jean François Aimé, comte (1749-1824). Campagne de 1794, ou 2me année de la République française, journaux des sieges qui ont été fait cette campagne. **Includes accounts of the sieges of Ypres, Nieuport, L'Ecluse, etc.; and the part played in these operations by troops of General Dejean in the campain of the Armée du Nord., 1794-1795; 170/294; Manuscript, 94pp. and map.
  - The Bloudy Book, or the Tragicall and Desperate End of Sir John Fites (alias) Fitz (London, ). **Transcription by Mrs Sarah Valentine, probably in the early 19th century., 1605; 170/295; Manuscript on vellum. 22 leaves.
  - Wright, M. Diary (Singleton, East New South Wales, Australia, ). **Transcription of diary of a surveyor, recording events in his daily life and in the life of the colony., January 1, 1847-November 17, 1847; Typescript, 148 leaves.
  - Martin, Maurice Camille. Voyage de Lyon à Constantinope, 1815/1819, 1-3 (France ). **The author was an ordinance officer under Mouton-Duvernet during the Hundred Days of 1815. Fearing arrest, he left Lyon for Constantinople as the representative of a leading French weavers firm. Also contain notes and statistics chiefly concerning commerce in the Levant., ca. 1870; *170/297: 1-3; Manuscript, 3 vol.; maps, tables.
  - Trelawny, Sir Henry. Notes of my Journey in 1795. **Account of travels in Germany, Switzerland and N. Italy., July 19, 1795-January 20, 1796; 170/298; Manuscript, 163pp.
  - Everitt, T. Diary of Spiritual Experiences (London, ). **Notes and observations on occurrences at seances held by Everitt, his wife, friends and casual acquaintances., February 10, 1871-February 2, 1904; 170/299; Manuscript, 594pp.
  - Krupin, Sylvia. Bread without Butter (ca. 1935). **Recollections of a trip with her brother made from Pasadena, California, to New York City during the depression years. Includes descriptions of their experiences hitch-hiking and riding on freight trains., *170/300; Typescript, 89 leaves.
  - Red Rock Mines, Inc., Phoenix, Arizona. Corporate Records (Phoenix, Arizona, ). **Includes charter, by-laws and minutes., 1939-1941; *170/301; Typescript, 1 vol.
  - Rosselli, Stefano (1598-1664). Descrizione delle chiese di Firenze e suoi contorni, e dell'armi, inscrizioni, & altre memorie che in quelle si veggono quest'anno 1657 (Florence ). **Description of the churches of Florence and their surroundings; ca. 3000 heraldic design; wash-drawings of major funeral monuments. Copy made by Gaetano Martini in, 1657 1733.; *170/302; Manuscript, 1007pp.
  - Saunderson, Nicholas (1682-1739). Lecture in Hydrostaticks, Pneumaticks, and Opticks (Cambridge ). **The volume also includes lectures on astronomy, sound, Mechanicks (by Mr. Wrigley), and a compendium of technical chronology. The lectures were probably transcribed by John Lord., ca. 1725; *170/303; Manuscript, 250pp.
  - Strange, John (1732-1799). Ministerial Correspondence (Venice ). Copies of his corresponence covering his official duties as British resident at Venice., October 10, 1773-April 12, 1786; *170/304: 1-3; Manuscript, 3 vol.
  - Powell, Janet. La Puente Valley Past and Present. (La Puente, California, )., 1937; *170/305; Typescript, photocopy 358 leaves.
  - Damas de Marrilac, Claude Charles, vicomte de 1731-ca 1800). Journal des troubles de la Martinique Martinique. **The writer was appointed governor of Martinique in 1783. After the French Revolution, civil war broke out on the island in June 1790. Includes copies of letters and documents., September 1, 1790-March 14, 1791; *170/306; Manuscript, 621pp.
  - Confradria de Senyor Sant Julian, Teruel, Spain. Esta es la ordenacion de la Confradria de Senyor Sant Julian de la ciudat de Tuel (Teruel ). Cf. Ferrari, pp.61-62., 1440; 170/307; Manuscript, on vellum. 50 leaves.
  - Cooper, Charles Henry (1808-1866). Annals of Cambridge (Cambridge: Warwick and Company, ). **Christopher Wordsworth's copy containing manuscript notes on the interleaved pages and in the text., 1843; *170/308; Vols.2-3.
  - Cook, James (1728-1779). Letter to the Commissioners of the Navy (Mile End, England? ). **This letter concerns the equipping of the Resolution and Discovery for Cook's third and last voyage., March 5, 1776; *170/309; Manuscript, one leaf.
  - Root, Virginia V. Following the Pot of Gold at the Rainbow's End in the Days of 1850: the Life of Mrs Susan Thompson Lewis Parrish of El Monte, California (s.l. s.a.). **Account of covered wagon trip from Independence, Missouri, to El Monte, with mention of the captivity of Olive Oatman among the Apache and Mojave Indians., *170/310; Typescript, photocopy. 10 leaves.
  - Powell, Daniel N. La Puente Valley and her Neighbors and the Pageant of La Puente Valley (La Puente, California s.a.)., *170/311; Typescript, photocopy. 27 leaves.
  - York (ship). Transactions on board the York, Henry Lascelles, Commander (Log book, ). **Log of the British East India Company's ship: England to Madras, China, Vaumpoa and back to England, calling at Java and St. Helena., November 22, 1743-December 16, 1745; *170/312; Manuscript, 211pp.
  - Newmark, Maurice Harris (1859-1929). Library Catalogue (Los Angeles, ). **Catalogue of Newmark's library. Newmark was a prominent Los Angeles resident., ca. 1885; *170/313; Manuscript, 1 vol.
  - St James Hotel, San Diego, California. Register (San Diego ). **The hotel was completed in 1886 by Peter Remondino, M.D. It was later called, under E.F. Arey, the Santa Rosa Hotel., February 2, 1886-February 28, 1887; September 28, 1889-April 16, 1890; *170/314: 1-3; Printed register, signed. 3 vol.
  - Crane, Walter (1845/1915). Lionel's Travels (London )., ca. 1880; 170/315; Manuscript, 18 leaves, with original ink drawings, and watercolour titlepage.
    See also: no.170/201: Lionel's Latitudes.
  - Cobbold, Richard (1797/1877). Geoffrey Gambado, or a Simple Remedy for Hypocondriacism [sic] and Melancholy Splenetic Humours, by a Humorist Physician (s.l. ). **Published by Dean & Son, London 1865. Accompanied by set of Bunbury's 12 engravings., *170/316; Manuscript, 168pp.
  - Rubeis, Hortensius de. Rufugio di Collevecchio (Italian ). **Legal document with detailed instructions for the building and equipment of a family chapel., ca. 1625; *170/317; Manuscript, 53 leaves.
  - Ainsworth, William Harrison (1805-1882). Collection of letters, pamphlets and ephemera relating to a banquet given for Ainsworth in Manchester. **Includes four letters from Ainsworth to John Evans, September and October 1881; W.E. A. Axon's memoir of Ainsworth; The Artist and the Author: a Statement of Facts by George Cruikshank (London, 1872)., September 15, 1881; 170/318; Manuscript and printed. 10 items.
  - Brougham and Vaux, Henry Peter Brougham, 1st baron (1778-1868). Letters to George Harris and J. Stewart from Brougham. **Accompanied by pamphlet on Harris as candidate for the Chair of History at University College, London (1860)., 1848-1865; 170/319; Manuscript, 38 items.
  - Friswell, James Hain (1825-1878). Only an Actor: a Drama in Three Acts. **Apparently unpublished and unproduced. Accompanied by letter about the plan to Friswell from the theatre manager Charles Dillon (January 21, 1860)., ca. 1859; 170/320; Manuscript, 132 leaves.
  - Blessington, marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of (1789-1849). Company Book (Gore House, Kensington, London, ). **Contains the names of guests entertained at Gore House, with weekly totals of guests. Names include Lord Brougham, Dickens, Disraeli, Bulwer-Lytton, Marryat and Thackeray., July 20, 1841-July 16, 1847; 170/321; Manuscript, 68 leaves.
  - Paulus Venetus (1372?-1429). Summa Naturalium (Rimini 1421). **The scribe was Iohannes de Beylario. First printed in Venice, 1476. Cf. Ferrari, pp.62-63., *170/322; Italian Manuscript, 140 leaves.
  - Inventory of the Library of a French Bishop (France ). **484 books, notorial copy of original document. Cf. Nicole Marzac, The Library of a French Bishop in the late XVth Century (Paris, 1974); Ferrari, pp.63-64., post 1588; *170/323; Manuscript, 14 leaves.
  - Graves, Robert (d. 1825). List of Initials, Ciphers, Monograms, and Emblems used by Various Early Artists and Engravers with Tentative Identifications., ca. 1800; 170/324; Manuscript, 357 leaves.
  - Haslewood, Joseph (1769-1833), ed. Ancient Critical Essays upon English Poets and Poësy (London: Robert Triphook, )., 1811; 170/325; 2 vol. **Author's copy, interleaved with manuscript letters, additional illustrations, etc.
  - Pilkington, Mrs Hannah. Hannah Pilkington, her Book. **Prayer and devotional essays in two hands, many addressed to her by her brother, J.M., 1672-1692; 170/326; Manuscript, 157 leaves.
  - Calkins Carriage Company, Los Angeles. Letters sent (Los Angeles, ). **Outgoing correspondence relating to the business signed by J.W. Calkins, D.C. Hough and Mrs E.E. Hough. Some accounts included., August 23, 1882-July 15, 1889; *170/327; Manuscript, 1 vol.
  - Reade, Charles (1814-1884). Drink (London: Printed by William Clowes, ). **Apparently unpublished. A play made from Zola's novel L'assomoir., ca. 1879; 170/328; Page Proofs, unbound, 71pp.
  - Cox, Palmer (1840-1924). Drawings for The Brownies: their Book. **The book itself was first published in New York, 1887., ca. 1887; 170/329; Original pen and ink drawings. 26 items.
  - Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of (1789-1849). Lady Jemima Heatherfield. **A short story published in The Keepsake for 1842 (London, 1842)., ca. 1841; *170/330; Manuscript pp.49-70 and pp.74-86.
  - Langton, Stephanus. Interpretationes nominum Hebrai-corum (England? s. XIII med.) About 7,000 entries. Formerly the property of W.W. Greg. Cf. Ferrari, pp.64-65., 170/331; Manuscript on vellum. 70 leaves.
  - Pope, Alexander (1688-1744). Letter to William Fortescue. **The letter concerns Edmund Curll, the London publisher, with whom Pope had several altercations. Fortescue was Pope's legal advisor., 1735; Manuscript, 1p.
  - Byron, George Gordon Byron, 6th baron (1788-1824). Poems (London s.a.). **Fore-edge painting of view of Newstead Abbey., 170/333
  - Niven, Frederick John (1878-1944). Justice of the Peace (London ). **Presentation copy from Rebecca West to H.G. Wells., ca. 1917; 170/334
  - Maunsell, Rev. George Edmond. Poems (Bath: Printed by Binns and Goodwin, ). Many of the poems were published in 1861., ca. 1850; 170/335; **Author's copy, copiously annotated with additional poems and corrections (1848-1861).
  - Davis, John Edward (1816-1877). Log of H.M.S. Samarang, Charles H. Paget, Esq., Captain., June 6, 1831-September 28, 1834; **26 panoramic sketches of the coast line of South America (fourteen in watercolour; twelve in pencil); five pen-and-ink charts of Maceio Bay, Panama, Acapulco, Mazatlan and Guaymas Harbor; etc.